gordonramsay.com 2018-08-17

# Privacy Policy | Gordon Ramsay

If you object to us using your personal data for these purposes, including direct marketing, please let us know using the email address provided in section 1. 

Where we use your email to communicate marketing information to you we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.

We will process your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected in connection with the provision of service to you, unless we have a legal right or obligation to retain the data for a longer period, or the data is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.

We may collect personal data related to employees, directors, authorised signatories, or other individuals associated with GRG’s existing or prospective corporate customers, business partners, and vendors.

b) from a company that employs you, if you are an employee of our existing or prospective customer, business partner, or vendor,

d) during networking events that we have either hosted, or sponsored, or attended; and/or

e) from publicly available sources (for example, your company website or social media sites, such as LinkedIn)

We may collect the following categories of personal data relating to our existing or prospective customers’, business partners’, and vendors’ employees, officers, authorised signatories, and other associated individuals:

g) any feedback you submitted about your experience.

If you object to us using your personal data for these purposes, including direct marketing, please let us know using the email address provided in section 1.

Where we use your email to communicate marketing information to you we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.[](file:///C:/Users/sallynguyen/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V1OE5D5P/GRG%20Website%20Notice%20v6%2024%20May%202018_AP%20Comments.docx#_msocom_1)

### **D – How long do we keep your personal data?**

We will process your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected in connection with your business relationship with us, unless we have a legal right or obligation to retain the data for a longer period, or the data is necessary for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims.[  
](file:///C:/Users/sallynguyen/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V1OE5D5P/GRG%20Website%20Notice%20v6%2024%20May%202018_AP%20Comments.docx#_msocom_1)

## 2.3 WEBSITE VISITORS

A - Sources of personal data of personal data

B - Personal data that we collect and process

C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?

D - How long do we keep your personal data?

### **A - SOURCES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We may obtain your personal data from the following sources:

a) from you directly (for example, at the time of subscribing to any services offered on our website, including but not limited to email mailing lists, interactive services or requesting further goods or services); and/or

b) from your device or browser.

If you contact us, we may keep a record of that correspondence.

### **B - PERSONAL DATA THAT WE COLLECT AND PROCESS**

a) name;

b) title

c) data of birth, and post code, if you are signed up to our e-newsletters;

d) email address;

e) operating system;

f) browser type;

g) information on the use of our website (for example, pages visited, geographical location, time spent on the website, online transactions);

h) cookie data (for more information please see our **[Cookie Notice](https://www.gordonramsay.com/gr/cookie-policy/)**[](https://www.gordonramsay.com/gr/cookie-policy/));

i) preferences regarding online marketing; and/or

j) IP address.

### **C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?**

**Website Visitors**  
  
---  
  
**We may use your personal data to:**

| 

**Our lawful basis for doing so is:  **

| 

**Our legitimate interests in doing so are:**

|   
  
Provide our website services to you

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Website Management

Promote our goods and services

Account Management

|   
  
Establish and manage our relationship

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Understand the market in which we operate

Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)

Account Management

|   
  
Learn about our websites(s) users’ browsing patterns and the performance of our website(s)

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Website Management

|   
  
Security

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Managing security, risk and crime prevention

Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)

|   
  
Let you know about our products, services and events that may be of interest to you by letter, telephone, email or other forms of electronic communication

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Promote our goods and services

Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)

|   
  
Learn about how our products or services may be used

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Understand the market in which we operate

Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)

|   
  
If you object to us using your personal data for the above purposes, including direct marketing, please send us an email using the email address in section 1.

Where we use cookies or similar technologies we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.

Where we use your email to communicate marketing information to you we will seek your prior consent where required to do so by law.

### **D – How long do we keep your personal data?**

We will keep your personal data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected in connection with your requests via our website or your use of our website.

## 2.4 JOB APPLICANTS

We may collect personal data related to job applicants for positions advertised on our website.

A - Sources of personal data

B - Personal data that we collect and process

C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?

D - How long do we keep your personal data?

### **A - SOURCES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We may obtain your personal data from the following sources:

a) from you directly;

b) from a third party, for example, individual referrals or a recruitment agency;

c) from our affiliates [see the list in Annex 1];

d) via web-based application forms;

e) during networking events that we have either hosted, or sponsored, or attended; and/or

f) from publicly available sources (for example, professional networks, such as LinkedIn).

### **B - PERSONAL DATA THAT WE COLLECT AND PROCESS  **

We may collect the following categories of personal data, which may differ, depending on the content of your CV or baseline documents you submit to us:

a) name;

b) residence address;

c) personal email address;

d) telephone number;

e) date of birth;

f) career and education history;

g) skills, experience, and qualifications;

h) personal interests, languages spoken, questionnaire results;

i) gender;

j) names and contact details for references. Please note that it is your responsibility to obtain consent from your references prior to providing us personal information about them;

k) current and historic salary details together with salary expectations;

l) details of your current benefit entitlements; and/or

m) information about your entitlement to work in the country in which the GRG EU affiliate is located.

### **C - WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND WHAT ARE OUR LAWFUL BASES FOR IT?**

**Job Applicants**  
  
---  
  
**We may use your personal data to:**

| 

**Our lawful basis for doing so is:  **

|   
  
Check your eligibility to work in the country in which GRG affiliate is located

| 

Legal obligation

|   
  
Where you provide us with information regarding your disability, we will process it as part of our legal obligation to make reasonable adjustments for recruitment process

| 

Legal obligation

|   
  
**We may use your personal data to:**

| 

**Our lawful basis for doing so is:  **

| 

**Our legitimate interests in doing so are:**  
  
---|---|---  
  
Facilitate the selection process

Assess and confirm your suitability for employment

Communicate with you

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

Talent Management (including at an intra-group level)  
  
Execute business process and internal management

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

Management Reporting (including at an intra-group level)  
  
Safeguard the security of our infrastructure, premises, assets and office equipment, including prevention of criminal activity, defending legal claims

| 

Legitimate interests

| 

Managing security, risk and crime prevention

Exercise or defend legal claims  
  
### **D – HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

We will keep and process your Personal Data only for as long as is necessary for the purposes for which it was collected. If you are successful and we hire you, we will keep your CV as part of your employee record for the duration of your employment with us. We will keep CVs and documents submitted by unsuccessful candidates for no longer than [six] months, unless we obtained their consent to keep it for longer. 

## 2.5 VISITORS TO OUR PREMISES

A - Sources of personal data

B - Personal data that we collect and process

C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?

D - How long do we keep your personal data?

### **A - SOURCES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We may obtain your personal data from you directly and from our systems’ records.

### **B - PERSONAL DATA THAT WE COLLECT AND PROCESS**

a) name;

b) business or personal contact details;

c) organisation;

d) role;

e) time and date of your visit; and/or

f) image (for example, from CCTV cameras at our premises).

### **C - WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND WHAT ARE OUR LAWFUL BASES FOR IT?**

**Visitors to our Premises**  
  
---  
  
**We may use your personal data to:**

| 

**Our lawful basis for doing so is:  **

| 

**Our legitimate interests in doing so are:**

|   
  
Security

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Managing security, risk and crime prevention

|   
  
Maintain records of visitors to our premises

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Management Reporting

|   
  
If you object to us using your personal data for the above purposes, please let us know using the email address provided in section 1.

### **D – HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

We keep your personal data for as long as necessary to ensure security of visitors to our premises and as soon as it is no longer necessary, usually after 90 days for CCTV, we delete it.

## 2.6 USERS OF WIFI

A - Sources of personal data

B - Personal data that we collect and process

C - Why do we collect your personal data and what are our lawful bases for it?

D - How long do we keep your personal data?

### **A - SOURCES OF PERSONAL DATA**

We may obtain your personal data from you directly and from our systems’ records.

### **B - PERSONAL  DATA THAT WE COLLECT AND PROCESS**

a) name;

b) title

c) email;

d) date of birth;

e) gender;

f) number of times wi-fi used;

g) and/or[](file:///C:/Users/sallynguyen/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V1OE5D5P/GRG%20Website%20Notice%20v6%2024%20May%202018_AP%20Comments.docx#_msocom_3)

h) device used.

### **C - WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL DATA AND WHAT ARE OUR LAWFUL BASES FOR IT?**

**Users of Wifi**  
  
---  
  
**We may use your personal data to:**

| 

**Our lawful basis for doing so is:  **

| 

**Our legitimate interests in doing so are:**

|   
  
Provide our wifi services to you

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Account management

Promote our goods and services

|   
  
Security

| 

Legitimate Interest

| 

Managing security, risk and crime prevention

|   
  
If you object to us using your personal data for the above purposes, please let us know using the email address provided in [section 1](file:///C:/Users/sallynguyen/AppData/Local/Microsoft/Windows/INetCache/Content.Outlook/V1OE5D5P/GRG%20Website%20Notice%20v6%2024%20May%202018_AP%20Comments.docx#_1._Who_is).

### **D – HOW LONG DO WE KEEP YOUR PERSONAL DATA?**

We keep your personal data for as long as necessary for you to use our internet connection. If you submitted other personal data about yourself, we will add it to your profile as a customer and keep it as long as you are our customer.

## **3\. WHO DO WE SHARE YOUR PERSONAL DATA WITH**

We do not sell your personal data to third parties.

#### **GRG’s Affiliates**

We may share your personal data with GRG’s affiliates (see the list in Annex 1) because we share the same guest management and IT systems. Transfers of personal data takes with GRG affiliates in the UK only. Such transfers are governed by GDPR compliant agreements between the affiliates for the integrity and confidentiality of personal data.

#### **Our Partner Organisations and Service Providers**

We may disclose information about you to organisations that provide a service to us, ensuring that they are contractually obligated to keep your personal data confidential and will comply with the GDPR and other relevant data protection laws.

We may share your information with the following types of service providers:

a) technical support providers who assist with our website and IT infrastructure,

b) third party software providers, including ‘software as a service’ solution providers, where the provider hosts the relevant personal data on our behalf;

c) professional advisers such as solicitors, accountants, tax advisors, auditors and insurance brokers;

d) providers that help us generate and collate reviews in relation to our goods and services;

e) our advertising and promotional agencies and consultants and those organisations or online platforms selected by us to carry out marketing campaigns on our behalf (for example, Facebook, Google, Instagram); and/or

f) service providers that assist us in providing our services.

#### Law enforcement or government bodies

We may disclose your personal data as permitted by law in order to investigate, prevent or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, violation of our intellectual property rights, situations involving potential threats to the physical safety of any person, violation of our Terms and Conditions or other agreements, or as required by law.

#### Company Mergers and Takeovers

We may transfer your personal data to potential purchasers and their advisors, subject to appropriate confidentiality obligations, in the event we decide to dispose of all or parts of our business.

## **4\. TRANSFERS OF PERSONAL DATA OUTSIDE THE EU/EUROPEAN ECONOMIC AREA**

We share personal data with external vendors or service providers or suppliers that we engage to perform services or functions on our behalf and under our instructions. Where these vendors are located within the EU, we ensure that they are contractually obligated to comply with the EU data protection rules.  We also ensure in our contracts with these organisations that they only Process Personal Data in accordance with our instructions and in order to provide the agreed services and protect the integrity and confidentiality of your personal data entrusted to them.

We may also disclose personal data to our advisers, consultants, law enforcement and other public authorities (such as tax and social security bodies), the police, prosecutors, courts and tribunals.  All these recipients are themselves responsible to comply with the EU data protection rules.

Some of the vendors that we engage to are located outside the European Economic Area. Where the EU Commission did not recognise them as locations providing adequate protection for personal data, we sign the EU Commission-approved contract (so called Standard Contractual Clauses) to protect your data.

You may request a copy of these agreements by contacting us using the email address in section 1.

## **5\. YOUR RIGHTS**

  * The GDPR provides you with certain rights in relation to the processing of your personal data, including to:
  * Request access to personal data about you (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you, and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * Request rectification, correction, or updating to any of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any inaccurate information we hold about you corrected.
  * Request personal data provided by you to be transferred in machine-readable format (“data portability”).
  * Request erasure of personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove personal data where you have exercised your right to object to processing (see below).
  * Request the restriction of processing of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of personal data about you (e.g. if you want us to establish its accuracy or the reason for processing it).
  * Object to the processing of your personal data in certain circumstances. This right may apply where the processing of your personal data is based on the legitimate interests of Company, as explained above.
  * Withdrawal of consent. If we rely on your consent (for example, when setting cookies on your device or for direct marketing), you may withdraw your consent at any time.
  * [These rights listed may be subject to various conditions under applicable data protection and privacy legislation.](https://www.gordonramsay.com/privacypolicy/restaurant-detail/)

If you would like to exercise any of your rights set out above, you can contact us by emailing using the email address in section 1.

### **[List of Kavalake affiliates](https://www.gordonramsayrestaurants.com/privacypolicy/restaurant-detail/)**
